Renzo Carpio

Career summary

I am a systems engineer from Ricardo Palma University. Professional with more than 10 years of experience in the IT area. Management of DevOps culture since 2017. I have 4 international certifications and more than 30 training courses.

Basic data

Full name: Renzo Eduardo Carpio Perez
 Mail: renzocarpiop@outlook.com

ID: 43981465 - 4
 Date of birth: 02/12/1986

Country: PeruMarital status: Married

Address: Avenida Sucre 1430 dpto 402, Magdalena

Cell phone: +51 944997490Skype: live:renzocarpiop

Summary of Qualifications

Skills:

LinuxDockerMiddlewareKubernetesITIL

(WAS, MQ,

Java, Shell, • AWS • Bitbucket

script

Devops,
Azure

Ol/CD

Artifactory

CI/CD ArtifactoryAgility Microservicios Lap

• Scrum • Architecture • Infrastructure as code

Jenkins
 Ansible
 Leadership

Languages:

Spanish (Native)
 English (Intermediate Level)

Career History

IT Senior Infrastructure Specialist – Middleware

January 2021 - Present

- I provide consulting, management and support at the infrastructure level of middleware platforms in production and pre-production environments: IBM Websphere MQ v6, v7, v7.5, v9 and v9.2 in distributed and Mainframe environments, IBM Websphere Application Server + IHS v7, v8 and v8.5, IBM Integration Bus v9, IBM Websphere Datapower XI52 and XG45, WMQFTE and CA – XCOM.
- Linux OS-level support: Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.6 and Centos 5.6

- I performed the resolution of problems / incidents and attention of tickets of requirements and changes according to ITIL in production and pre-production environments.
- Performed security hardening, managed and applied patches / updates to platforms.
- Made scripts to automate infrastructure tasks and provision resources at the middleware level.

Tools used

- IBM Websphere MQ v6, v7, v7.5, v8, v9 and v9.2.
- IBM Integration Bus v9 and v10.
- WMQFTE
- Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.6
- RSA

- IBM Websphere Application Server + IHS v7, v8, v8.5.5 y v9.
- IBM Websphere Datapower XI52 and XG45
- CA XCOM.
- IBM AIX operating system
- JBoss

Interbank, Lima, Peru

April 2020 – January 2021

Senior Devops Specialist

- Define the operation and management model of the devops toolchain (JIRA / BitBucket / Confluence / Jenkins / Artifactory / Sonarqube).
- Review, propose and lead: a) improvements to the implemented architecture of the devops toolchain and b) automation initiatives for the provisioning of infrastructure in Ansible, under Infrastructure as Code (IaC).
- Manage with vendors annual license/support costs of the devops toolchain.
- Provide methodological and technological advice in devops to the team of previous environments
- Prepare a devops toolchain integration roadmap against Active Directory.
- Support for k8s microservices and docker containers configured in Azure.
- Management of Python scripting for the automation of debugging processes in devops tools.

Tools used

- Atlassian Jira software
- Atlassian Bitbucket
- Sonarqube
- Docker
- Jenkins
- Python

- Atlassian Confluence
- Jfrog Artifactory
- Microsoft Azure
- kubernetes
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)

IBM del Perú, Lima, Peru

May 2012 - March 2020

Subject Matter Expert (SME) Devops Specialist

June 2019 – March 2020

- Provide advice and mentorship to the devops team in relation to agile practices/devops mindset.
- and technologies (use, support and administration)

- Solve difficult situations with the client and the team.
- L3 support for problems/incidents in production or pre-production environments for critical applications.

Tools used

- Atlassian Jira software
- Atlassian Bitbucket
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Docker
- Red Hat OpenShift
- MongoDB
- IBM Http Server v8 y v8.5
- IBM DataPower XI52 and XG45

- Atlassian Confluence
- Jfrog Artifactory
- Microsoft Azure
- kubernetes
- Jenkins
- IBM Websphere Application Server v8 y v8.5
- IBM MQ v8
- IBM Integration BUS v9 y v10

Site Reliability Engineer (SRE)

August 2018 - May 2019

- Manage and support at the infrastructure level the following technologies in production and pre-production environments: Jenkins, GitLab / Bitbucket / MongoDB / Docker / Kubernetes / Azure (PAAS) / RHEL 7 Atomic Host and RHEL 7 / Red Hat OpenShift Container Platform 3.9 / IBM WebSphere Application Server 8.5, MQ 7, 8 and 9; Message Broker 8, Integration Bus 9, and 10.
- L2 support for problems/incidents in production or pre-production environments for critical customer applications Banco de Crédito del Perú.

Tools used

- Atlassian Jira software
- Atlassian Bitbucket
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Docker
- Red Hat OpenShift
- MongoDB
- IBM Http Server v8 y v8.5
- IBM DataPower XI52 and XG45

- Atlassian Confluence
- Jfrog Artifactory
- Microsoft Azure
- kubernetes
- Jenkins
- IBM Websphere Application Server v8 y v8.5
- IBM MQ v8
- IBM Integration BUS v9 y v10
- Git

IT Devops Specialist

December 2017 – July 2018

- I actively participated in team ceremonies under the Scrum framework, which
 allowed to secure (together with the development team) CI/CD as part of the SDLC.
 Provide at the infrastructure level to support and execute orders of production
 changes and certification for the agile team Nuevo Home Banking of the client
 Banco de Crédito del Perú.
- L1 support for problems/incidents in production or pre-production environments for the project.

Tools used

- Atlassian Bitbucket
- Docker

kubernetes

- MongoDB
- IBM Http Server v8 y v8.5
- IBM DataPower XI52 and XG45
- Git

- Jenkins
- IBM Websphere Application Server v8 y v8.5
- IBM Integration BUS v9 and v10
- IBM MQ v8

IT Senior Infrastructure Specialist – Middleware

September 2014 – November 2017

- Managed and provided support at the infrastructure level of middleware platforms in production and pre-production environments: IBM Websphere MQ v6, v7, v7.5 and v8 in distributed and Mainframe environments, IBM Websphere Application Server + IHS v7, v8 and v8.5, IBM Integration Bus v9, IBM Websphere Datapower XI52 and XG45, WMQFTE and CA – XCOM.
- Linux OS-level support: Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.6 and Centos 5.6
- I performed the resolution of problems / incidents and attention of tickets of requirements and changes according to ITIL in production and pre-production environments.
- Performed security hardening, managed and applied patches / updates to platforms.
- Made scripts to automate infrastructure tasks and provision resources at the middleware level.

Tools used

- IBM Websphere MQ v6, v7, v7.5, v8
- IBM Integration Bus v9
- WMQFTE
- Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.6
- IBM Websphere Application Server + IHS v7, v8 y v8.5
- IBM Websphere Datapower XI52 and XG45
- CA XCOM.
- IBM AIX operating system

Supervisor in the area of Incident and Event Monitoring.

May 2012 - August 2014

- Managed the attention of critical problems / incidents according to ITIL in production environments for the client Banco de Crédito del Perú.
- I managed the attention of requirements in production environments according to
- Managed the attention of events or alerts in production environments.

Support in the area of Incident and Event Monitoring.

July 2011 – April 2012

 Attention of incidents and events of a critical nature for Banco de Crédito del Perú, generation of daily reports and follow-up of incidents derived to L2 or L3 supports according to ITIL in the production environment.

Education

Certifications

- 07/2022: AWS Partner: Accreditation (Tech and Business) y Cloud Economics
- 09/2021: AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- 05/2021: Azure Fundamentals AZ-900
- 08/2020: Professional Scrum Master I (Scrum.org)
- 11/2019: Certified Kubernetes Administrator
- 07/2016: IBM Certified System Administrator WebSphere MQ V7
- 05/2013: ITIL v3 ® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management

Courses (Last 4 years)

- 08/2022: ZA950G: WebSphere Application Server V9 Administration.
- 06/2022: Interskill IBM MQ Operations and Administration Expert (20 hrs).
- 07/2020: Scrum Master training + Prepare for the PSM I ® certification + PSM 1
- 06/2020: Devops Master Certification (Official course)
- 11/2019: LFS258: Kubernetes Fundamentals (Official course)
- 04/2019: Exam AZ-100: Microsoft Azure Infrastructure and Deployment (Official course)
- 02/2019: DO280: Red Hat Openshift Administration I (Official course)
- 10/2018: MongoDB Basics (Official course)